Kritika Uma Shankar

Sandy, Utah 84070 • (408) 429-9497

kritikaumashankar@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kritikaumashankar

Focussed and quick learning Software Engineer with 3.5 years of experience in programming who is proficient in Java, HTML, CSS and Javascript. Bringing in depth experience in software design, maintenance, as well as the ability to work with new and existing codes.

Skills

Software: Java (8 and lower), J2EE, Javascript, SQL, React, HTML,CSS, Spring, JSON, Next.js, NodeJS(Express), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST API, Spring Boot.

Tools: Tortoise SVN, Eclipse IDE, Git, Heroku, AWS(S3 Bucket), Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Apache Tomcat, Figma, Sketch.

Certification

The University of Utah, Professional Education, Salt Lake City, Utah Full-time Web Development Certificate, DevPoint Labs

Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

Experience

Senior System Engineer

Apr 2013 - Jun 2014

Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Technologies: Java 6, Struts, JSP, MS SQL, Javascript, SVN, HTML, CSS, Oracle

- Implemented a scheduler to store data in a database from XML by doing an API call for a migration project and performed Unit and Integration testing.
- Enhanced and added new functionality to the existing email application for better UI usage to improve user experience.
- Proactively resolved all the reported bugs and took part in support.

System Engineer

Dec 2010 - Mar 2013

Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Technologies: Java 6, Struts, JSP, DB2, Springs, SVN, Javascript, EJB, SOAP

- Involved in Analysis, Build and Test phase of enterprise application called **Express Pass** (American Express client).
- Optimized the performance of the application by writing DB queries into Stored Procedures.
- Integrated Spring(Dependency Injection) into the application as a POC. Received appreciation from Team Lead and Project Manager after successfully completing it.
- Responsible for post production support and maintenance by resolving reported bugs.
- Performed thorough Manual testing (Unit and Integration testing) on the application in all environments.

Education

K C G College Of Technology, Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics
Sept 2006 - May 2010

Projects

Eat Well, Live Well Dec 2020 - Present

https://eatwelllivewell.in/

- This is a website created for a client who is a Nutritionist.
- It is developed in Nextis, for the Contact page Twilio SendGrid API is used.
- Figma is used for designing the website to get approval of the design.
- Phase 1 of the project is Static Website. Phase 2 is in the design process which will be app to store the progress of the clients.

Portfolio Website: Oct 2018 - Present

https://www.kritikaumashankar.info/

- Developed in React for front-end and Node.js for BackEnd.
- MongoDB is used to store the number of clicks.
- Nodemailer for sending email.
- Used GitHub API for displaying the projects in the Work section.

Enterprise International:

Sep 2018 - Oct 2018

- Developed a travel website for Enterprise International by a team of 5 people as part of the final project during bootcamp.
- Technologies: React, styled-component, Semantic, Rails, PostgreSQL,Rspec
- Designed and developed Destinations(for both normal and admin users), Contact Us, Register pages.
- Implemented test scripts and performed testing with different test cases for the back-end development (developed in Rails) using RSpec.